DAVID EISENMENGER

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

A user experience designer and researcher with a diverse background in product design, social work, and healthcare management. My focus is to solve problems with solutions that create a seamless user experience, make people happy, and add value to the product. My approach uses humancentered design in eliciting user needs and goals working creatively and collaboratively toward solutions.

CONTACT

101 Stevenson Ave Louisville, KY 40206

502.468.4978 david@heronblue.design www.heronblue.design

SKILLS

Research

Interview

Survey

Content Strategy

Usability Testing

Design

Persona

Journey Mapping

Wireframing Prototyping

Tools

Axure RP, Balsamiq, Sketch Adobe Creative Suite

InVision

Languages

HTML CSS

EXPERIENCE

Freelance

Dec 2017 - Present

User Experience Designer

Conducting end to end design and research. Recent projects include research and interactive design for web and mobile.

Friendship Health and Rehab Director of Social Services

Feb 2016 - April 2019

Focus on customer experience and patient wellbeing. Enhanced patient care related to Social Services from the 15th percentile (national) to "deficiency free" status in all 42 areas of Quality of Care as measured by CMS annual survey. (2016-2019)

Signature Healthcare, LLC

May 2013 - Feb 2016

Director of Education & Research

Researched, developed, and directed palliative care program piloted at 5 long term care facilities across a regional network. Researched, developed and delivered diversity and inclusion program for use with front line staff in 13 long term care facilities in urban markets.

Signature Healthcare, LLC

Oct 2009 - May 2013

Director of Spirituality

Led initiatives focused on patient and staff wellbeing. In a high turnover field, average monthly nursing turnover reduced by a 3% in 12 month period. Community Outreach Award for program adding value to the patient, family, community connection. CMS deficiency free annual surveys 2012, 2013.

EDUCATION

User Experience Design

May 2018 - June 2019

Springboard

Front End Web Development Track

Sept 2017 - Mar 2018

Code Louisville

M.A. Marriage and Family Therapy

Aug 2005 - May 2007

Louisville Presbyterian Theological Seminary

B.A. Peace and Global Studies

Aug 1999 - May 2001

Earlham College